Amit Sargar

Java-Angular Fullstack Developer • 10+ Years' Experience

■ amitsargar@gmail.com • • +91 9595 666 995 • in amitsargar • • asargar.github.io

SUMMARY

Full-stack developer with over 10 years of experience specializing in Java (Spring Boot) and Angular. As an Assistant Vice President at Deutsche Bank, I lead high-impact engineering projects, including multiteam OpenShift migrations and scalable dashboard deployments. I am recognized for delivering secure, maintainable applications on schedule and driving cloud-first solutions and enterprise-grade microservices.

SKILLS

Backend Java, Spring Boot, REST, Microservices, Hibernate
Frontend Angular, TypeScript, RxJS, NGRX, HTML, CSS
DevOps Jenkins, OpenShift, Helm, Docker, Kubernetes, CI/CD
Testing & Quality JUnit, Mockito, Jest, WebDriverIO, Sealights, SonarQube

Version Control Git, GitHub, Bitbucket

Monitoring Splunk

Work Experience

Assistant Vice President, Deutsche Bank, Pune

Mar 2020 - Present

- Promoted to Assistant Vice President based on a proven track record of technical excellence.
- **Spearheaded** the OpenShift (OCP 3 to 4) migration for **5 teams**, upskilling developers to perform migrations independently and **improving overall application reliability**.
- Architected and implemented a configuration-based, reusable, and scalable dashboard framework, which
 reduced the development effort for new dashboards by 70%.
- Enhanced Monitoring and Observability capabilities by adding action-specific performance tracking.
- Introduced production error count reports on Splunk, reducing production (including silent ones)
 errors by 40%.
- Implemented a robust disaster recovery strategy, increasing system resilience.
- Collaborated with **cross-functional teams** to deliver features and maintain business **SLAs**.

Consultant, Deloitte Consulting USI, Mumbai

Dec 2016 – Mar 2020

- Progressed from Analyst to Consultant and managed key deliverables on modernization projects.
- Upgraded client's insurance payment gateway to PCI-DSS compliance, significantly enhancing the user experience.
- Represented Deloitte in the Code Gladiators, a national coding event recognized by the Guinness World Records.
- Designed and developed **multi-tenant REST APIs** for secure client portal interactions.

Associate Software Engineer, Pragmatix Services, Mumbai

Jan 2015 - Dec 2016

- Developed internal tooling for Smart Search, Download Automation, and Reporting Dashboards, improving data visibility and efficiency.
- Co-designed and implemented Rule Engines for NPA/EWS detection.

EDUCATION